Justin Heath

Full-Stack Developer

Professional Statement

Passionate about implementing user-friendly platforms with simple functionality but with a big impact on productivity and accuracy.

Attending 'Leeds Digital Festival' in 2017 opened my eyes to the possibilities coding had to offer and igniting a fire to achieve more in the digital sector than I ever could in finance. 3 years ago I transitioned into a full-stack web developer role after completing 15 years in the finance department, all in the NHS.

I enjoy how full-stack development gives me the skills to rapidly go from 'discussion' to 'concept' to 'deployment', as my knowledge and skills grow this becomes even more enjoyable.

"Opportunities to work with Justin are always an exciting time where his creative solutions tear barriers previously in place and always lead to the perfect balance of efficiency/relevance."

Taso Gazis Diabetes & Endocrinology consultant @ NUH

I am seeking the perfect opportunity that will assist me in achieving my goal of becoming a senior software developer where I can support and guide the next generation of developers. In return you gain a passionate individual who is keen to grow with the department, years of softs skills harnessed ready to work closely with users to exceed their expectations. I complement these skills with a constant desire to learn and evolve where I never back down from a challenge and enjoy the opportunity to learn and share.

Recent Projects

Nottinghamshire COVID Vaccination Programme (Solo Project)

- Scoped, designed and built a vaccination CRUD page within our intranet site to run off lists of patients to contact to invite for C19 vaccine. The complexity in this project was the restrictions of the cohort of patients to invite i.e. certain underlying illnesses, etc.
- The benefit this realised: Prevention of hundreds if not thousands of staff members having to individually go into each patient record to ensure they did not have excluded issues. My web app automated the process, improved accuracy and prevented wrongly sent invites therefore patients where not refused the vaccine at vaccine site (which was the most common process in other counties i.e. invite then reject).

COVID Staffing and PPE Register (Networked Project)

- · Scoped, designed and built a web application for all GP practices in Nottinghamshire to report the daily COVID status of their staff and PPE stock levels in line with national guidelines. This information was submitted to the government and used by senior teams across the Nottinghamshire Healthcare System.
- The benefit this realised: Enable to the senior teams to proactively reallocated staff and PPE across Nottinghamshire which prevented any of the providers from shutting.

Mailing and Newsletter System (Joint Project)

- Design and build a mailing system to communicate with 10,000 NHS staff across Nottinghamshire. The biggest challenge was collating individuals contact details into a central repository, aligning this with their job role and department. This created several smaller projects around the control and updating of this data.
- The benefit this realised: Centralised data source of all staff members which proved key when the pandemic hit to getting vital information to the right NHS staff member.

Relevant Experience

Software Developer - Nottingham & Nottinghamshire CCG - 2017 — Present Company Description – Control the funding for all healthcare in Nottinghamshire.

- UI development utilising HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- · Support all data imports into the data warehouse using Visual Studio Suite (SSIS and SSAS).
- · Building tables and views in SQL, updating data with T-SQL in SP's & SQL agent jobs.

Senior Accountant - Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust - 2015 — 2017

Company Description - Primary acute healthcare provider in Leeds.

- Led the theatres paperless/automated stocking system project and data loads into trust database. Led the clinical engagement project to increase clinical ownership of costing data held and used.
- Supported the wider costing dept to complete annual national costing submissions to government.

Accountant - Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust - 2007 - 2014

Company Description – Primary acute healthcare provider in Nottingham.

- Led the paperless transformation of the cashiers dept, built the systems & documentation/training.
- Led the paperless transformation of journals, 10,000 rows a month previously entered manual I automated.

 Transformed an excel based costing system to a graphical information journey built by me in QlikView.

 This allowed the users of the data to drill down and explore the validity of the data autonomously.

CONTACT

justin@justcoder.fun

Nottingham, UK

Skills

Programming languages:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, React.js, Node.js, npm & C#

Data Management:

SQL (SQL Server, T-SQL and PostgreSQL), Visual Studio Suite (SSAS, SSRS, SSIS)

Debugging:

Proficient user of devtools for identifying bugs and Git and Github for version control.

Creativity:

Able to implement visually appealing and functional design elements.

Problem solving:

Skilled in bridging the gap between creative concepts from UX designers and practical front-end implementation.

Leadership:

Trained and mentored interns and work placement students.

Education

Purple Beard Training

Coding Boot Camp (2021 Jan - Mar) w3school Front-End Certificate

Kaplan Online

Accounting AAT (2010 - 2014) Level 2,3 & 4

Derby University

A Levels (2001 - 2003) Maths, Physics & Computer Science

Interests

Volunteering in the 'Canal Trust' Walking and Running Researching & Learning Technologies Network with 'TechNotts' & 'York Dev' Attend MeetUps in the Tech Community

Reference

Removed for web version